字幕翻译/压制：NeXT-X6，旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/u4r0yrF_Wa0
原视频发布日期：20200514
原作者名：Everyday Astronaut
嗨 这里是Tim Dodd 每日宇航员
- Hi, it's me Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut.
你有没有过不小心错用汤匙而非茶匙？
Have you ever accidentally used a tablespoon instead of a teaspoon?
或者 也许你为了拧一个9/16英寸螺栓 而拿了一把公制扳手
Or maybe you grabbed a metric wrench when you were trying to loosen up a 9/16" bolt?
或者 也许你听到有人说东西重达一吨 你得去问他们
Or maybe you've heard someone say that something weighs a ton and you have to ask them,
你用的是一英吨还是一公吨
now is that a imperial ton or a metric ton?
幸运的是 当我们大多数人混淆了单位
Luckily, when most of us mix up units,
它可能只会导致我们的食物变得难吃
it likely just leads to our food tasting bad,
也许是拧坏一个螺栓
or maybe strips a bolt,
或只是简单地导致一个非常烦人的争论
or just simply leads to a really annoying argument
争论于它们哪个是合适的测量系统
between which is the right measurement system.
但当NASA和洛克希德·马丁公司搞混了火星气候探测器的单位
But when NASA and Lockheed Martin mixed up the units for the Mars Climate Orbiter,
这就搞砸了价值3.27亿美元的火星探测任务
it led to the loss of a $327 million mission to Mars.
facepalm翻译出自av45444894
欢迎来到另一集航天史上最尴尬的时刻 也可称之为尴尬航天
Welcome to another episode of biggest facepalms of spaceflight history, otherwise known as spacepalms.
现在我们来看一看任这个务
This is where we're going to take a look at a mission
或者说一个事件 几乎导致密歇根所有人集体扶额叹息的事件
or an event that almost certainly lead to everyone in Michigan troll collectively facepalming.
现在这一个 具体说是一个非常著名的故事
Now this one in particular is a very well known story.
一个你可能已经从你的物理老师那里听过的故事
One you may have heard your physics professor regale you
在讨论单位的重要性时
with when talking about the importance of units.
不过说实话 我不认为我实际上已经听到了完整的 正确的故事
But honestly, I don't think I've actually heard the correct story all the way through
我在做这个视频之前也绝对不知道真正发生了什么
and I definitely didn't know what truly happened before I made this video.
所以今天 让我们来看看本来应该发生的事情
So today, let's take a look at what was suppose to happen,
最后发生了什么以及为什么
what wound up happening and why.
毕竟这是会代代相传的经典一课
After all, this is a classic lesson that will be passed down for generations and generations.
而且这是一个有趣的故事
And it's a fun story to tell.
所以 让我们开始吧
So, let's get started.
-  [任务控制]三 二 一
- [Mission Control] Three, two, one,
起飞
and liftoff!
-  [尼尔]这是对人类的一小步
- [Neil] That's one small step for man.
-  [任务控制]这是休斯敦和一号测试的通信
- [Mission Control] That's Houston contact for the test one.
1999年 那时的网站还长这个样子
The year 1999, back when websites look like this.
黑客帝国刚刚上映 Cher的歌曲Believe还是头号热单
"The Matrix" was released and the Cher song "Believe" was the number one hit.
NASA也希望能有一个大手笔
NASA was hoping to have a big hit on their hands as well
一个令人兴奋的新火星轨道探测器 它将会研究火星的气候
with an exciting new Mars Orbiter that would study the Martian climate,
正如你猜的那样 它被命名为 火星气候探测器
known as you guessed it, the Mars Climate Orbiter.
NASA为一些成本较低 体积较小的探测器制定了新的指导方针 用于行星间任务
NASA set new guidelines for some less expensive and smaller probes for interplanetary missions
在1994年成立了一个小型航天器技术小组后
after a panel on small spacecraft technology was formed in 1994.
这些新的探测器将在1000公斤以下 并配备更多专门的科学仪器
These new probes would be under 1000 kilograms with more focused scientific instruments
而不是像多年前的那种瑞士军刀式 一锅端式的航天器
instead of Swiss Army knife do it all style spacecraft from years prior.
这一新计划的第一个任务名为 火星全球勘测者 于1996年
The first mission in this new program was called the "Mars Global Surveyor" which launched in 1996,
从卡纳维拉尔角太空军基地SLC-17A发射台上的Delta II发射
on top of a Delta II from SLC-17A Cape Canaveral Space Force Station,
或着说卡纳维拉尔角空军基地 当时它是这个名字
or Cape Canaveral Air Force Station, as it was known at the time.
这第一个探测器将绘制出比以往更详细的火星表面图
This first probe would map the surface of Mars with more detail than ever before,
这将有助于为未来的火星登陆器铺平道路
which would help pave the way for future Mars landers.
火星气候探测器是继火星全球勘测者的成功之后
The Mars Climate Orbiter was to follow the success of the Mars Global Surveyor
将携带一些仪器
and would be taking with it some of the instruments
最初为火星全球勘测者设计的仪器
that were originally designed for the Mars Global Surveyor.
两者将成为从轨道上研究火星的小型研究站
The two would be a mini powerhouse for studying Mars from orbit.
飞船宽2.1m
The spacecraft found up being 2.1 meters wide.
高1.6m 长2m
1.6 meters tall and two meters deep.
它仅重638kg
It would weigh only 638 kilograms
这让它能够被只有四个固体火箭助推器的德尔塔II火箭发着
making it capable of being launched on a Delta II with only four solid rocket boosters,
尽管它的体积小
but despite its small way,
它仍然塞满了科学仪器 包括火星轨道器照相机
it was still stuffed to the gills with scientific instruments including the Mars Orbiter Camera,
火星轨道器激光测高仪 热辐射光谱仪
the Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter, the Thermal Emission Spectrometer,
一个磁力计和电子反射计
a Magnetometer and electron reflectometer,
超稳定振荡器和火星中继信号接收器
the ultra-stable oscillator and a Mars Relay signal receiver.
大声说这些仪器感觉就像我编了其中的一半
Saying those out loud feels like I was making half of them up,
我可能应该试着偷偷随便扯些名词写进去
I probably should have tried to sneak in the specs on the end line for the rotary girder
来看看你们有没有走神
to see if any you guys are actually paying attention.
探测器有八个单组元推进器
The vehicle had eight monoprop thrusters
每个有22N的推力 用于轨道修正
each with 22 Newtons of thrust for trajectory corrections
四个较小的0.9N的推进器用于姿态控制
and four smaller 0.9 Newton thrusters for attitude control.
最后 它有一个较大的主引擎 莱罗斯 1B
Lastly, it had one larger main engine a LEROS 1B
为火星进入机动点火提供640N的推力
that provided 640 Newtons of thrust for the Mars insertion burning.
火星气候探测器有一个独特的设计
Mars Climate Orbiter had a unique design.
它只有一个大的太阳能电池板位于一侧
It only had a single large solar panel off to one side,
这是能够在火星产生500瓦电力
which was capable of 500 watts at Mars,
另一方面 因为火星比地球离太阳远50%
which side note because Mars is 50% further away from the Sun than the Earth is,
由于平方反比定律 火星上太阳能电池板的功率约为地球上的45%
due to the inverse square law, a solar panel on Mars is about 45% as powerful as it is on Earth.
1998年12月11日 UTC 18:45
On December 11th 1998, at 18:45 UTC,
火星气候探测器从卡纳维拉尔角空军基地的SLC-17A发射台起飞
the Mars Climate Orbiter took off from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station SLC-17A
开始其10个月的旅程前往火星
beginning its 10 month journey to Mars.
这次发射中我最喜欢的一件事是
One of my favorite things about this launch is
Star-48B自旋稳定固体第三级
the Star-48B spin stabilized solid propellant third stage.
没错 它是自旋稳定的 所以如果在推力上有什么小的偏移
That's right, its spin stabilize So if there's any minor offset in the thrust,
你可以通过分级旋转来知道
you can know it out by spinning the stage.
一旦点火燃烧完毕
Once the burn is complete,
有一个溜溜球式反自转机制大致知道旋转的状态
there's a YoYo Despin mechanism that mostly knows how the spin,
正是这样的东西让我认为是如此的酷
it‘s stuff like this that I think is just so cool.
于是这个小探测器上路了 一切看起来都不错
So the little probe was on its way, everything looking good.
像所有的深空飞行任务那样
And like all deep space missions,
一路上几次轨迹修正点火以确保瞄准目标 这是正常不过的事情
it's normal to do a few correction burns along the way to make sure you nail your target.
也不是什么大不了事 我是说 每次都是这么做的
And that's no big deal I mean, this is done all the time.
四次方向修正进行于 1998年12月21日
There were four course corrections performed on December 21st 1998,
3月4日 7月25日和1999年9月15日
March 4th, July 25th and September 15th 1999.
在火星进入机动点火开始的前一天 还计划有一次可选的方向修正
There was another optional course correction planned just one day prior to the Mars insertion burn,
但被管理团队拒绝
but it was denied by management
因为根据以往的轨道 他们认为探测器没有偏离方向
because they thought based on prior trajectories that the probe was on course.
除了方向修正
Alongside the course corrections,
飞船还进行一些所谓的角动量去饱和 或称为AMD
the spacecraft also perform something called angular momentum desaturations or AMDs.
许多航天器做到这一点 但尤其是火星气候轨探测
Many spacecraft do this but especially the Mars Climate Orbiter,
因为它有这样的单面太阳能电池板
because it had that single sided solar panel.
它的一半比另一半经历了比其他航天器更多的太阳光压
It experienced more solar pressure on one half of the spacecraft than the other.
对了 有趣的一点是
By the way, fun side note,
太阳光压是无质量的光子对航天器施加压力的动量
solar pressure is the momentum of the massless photons exerting pressure on a spacecraft
而不是太阳风
and it's not solar wind.
太阳风是由太阳喷出的具有质量的粒子如核子和电子组成的
Solar wind is composed of particles with mass ejected by the sun like nucleons and electrons.
感谢Scott Manley和Twitter众网友帮助我澄清理解这个知识点
Thanks to Scott Manley and the rest of space Twitter for helping clarify that for me.
好了 所以你的飞船永远轻微地在一个你不想要的方向旋转
Okay, so your spacecraft is ever so slightly rotating in a direction you don't want.
而为了使飞船内帮助维持方向的反应轮
And in order to keep the reaction wheels inside the spacecraft
不至于超时工作
that helped maintain orientation from having to work overtime,
你可以进行AMD 将飞船重新设定回理想的方向
you can perform an AMD to reset the spacecraft back to its ideal orientation
让这些反应轮开心 不至于超时工作
and keep those reaction wheels happy and not overworked.
现在 每一次航天器执行任何角动量去饱和机动
Now each and every single time the spacecraft performs any desaturation maneuver
或任何修正点火
or any correction burn,
还是任何机动 每个推进器点火的 每一次精确的冲量或确切的时间都会被记录
or really any maneuver the exact impulse or the exact amount of time each and every thruster is fired, is recorded,
然后送回地球
and then that's sent back down to earth
所以任务控制中心可以计算出飞船究竟改变了多少它的轨道
so Mission Control can calculate exactly how much the spacecraft change its trajectory.
即使是极微小的机动幅度
Even if it's by the teentiest, tiniest amount during these corrections.
但现在你要知道 任务控制中心仍然可以追踪探测器的位置
But now mind you mission control can still track the probe
以及其去往火星深空轨道
and its trajectory in deep space on the way to Mars.
但是 这样做的主要方法是利用多普勒频移
But the primary way of doing so is using Doppler shift
而这在旅程某些部分上的准确度并不好
and that's not incredibly accurate at some portions of the journey,
尤其是当速度的变化与有利位置垂直时
especially when the changes in velocity are perpendicular to the vantage point.
可以这样想 多普勒可以非常精确地判断出某物是在加速还是在减速
Think of it like this Doppler can very precisely tell if something is speeding up or slowing down,
是在直行 远离还是在向你移动
moving straight, away or towards you.
但从地球的有利位置来看 它并不能真正判断出某物是否在横向加速
But it can't really tell if something is speeding up side to side from Earth's vantage point,
而在前往火星的旅程中 有很大一部分时间正是如此
which for a good portion of the journey to Mars, is exactly what's happening.
所以通常 制导团队会精确计算出探测器的准确轨迹
So generally guidance teams will precisely calculate the vehicle's exact trajectory
在将探测器送往火星的霍曼转移点火燃烧后
after the Hohman transfer burn that sends the probe on its way to Mars.
而只要任何外力不作用在探测器上 剧透下 譬如它的空间(位置)
And so long as any outside force doesn't act upon the vehicle, which spoiler, its space.
这些变量都是被解释以及熟知的
The variables are well accounted for and well known.
探测器会最终到达计算出的位置 精确到令人惊讶的程度
The vehicle will end up exactly where it's calculated to a surprising degree of accuracy.
但是 这也意味着他们需要考虑每一次推进器点火
But this also means that they need to account for each and every thruster fire
因为即使是那些微小的冲量也会改变探测器的具体目的地
as even those tiny little impulses change the exact destination of the vehicle.
即使只有一个很小的量 如果你做东西足够
Even if only a tiny amount, if you do something enough,
最终随着时间的推移 它会有非常大的变化
it ends up adding up over time to a very drastic change.
当然 当你的目标是一个距离你超过2亿公里的星球时
Now, of course when you're aiming at a planet that's over 200 million kilometers away from you,
一个微小的误差要么意味着错过这个星球
a tiny error could either mean missing that planet,
要么更糟的是 直接撞上它
or perhaps even worse, smacking right into it.
而NASA的瞄准计划只错过火星200公里左右
And NASA was aiming to only miss Mars by 200 kilometers or so.
所以容错率极低
So there was very little room for error.
而在一般情况下
And in general,
你要瞄准并尽可能地安全接近那个你想要被捕获的行星
you want to aim and get as close as you can safely get to the planet that you're trying to be captured by.
现在 当然 如果这是一个有大气层的行星
Now, of course, if you're on a planet that has an atmosphere,
因此就需要考虑不能靠太近
you need to take that into consideration and not get too low.
但距离越近 被捕获进入轨道所需的能量就越少
But the closer you are, the less energy it takes to get captured into orbit.
1999年9月15日 距离与火星相遇并开始进入机动点火只有一个星期
On September 15th 1999 just one week prior to the Mars encounter and insertion burn,
NASA进行了第四次也是最后的轨道修正机动
NASA performed the fourth and final trajectory correction maneuver,
将探测器置于火星地表上方226公里的轨道
which placed its trajectory 226 kilometers above the surface of Mars.
非常适合火星轨道进入
Perfect for the Mars orbital insertion.
但那次点火之后
But following that burn,
导航团队注意到他们的计算和他们的观察结果不匹配
the navigation team noticed their calculations and their observations didn't match.
而事实上
And in fact,
观测到的轨道越来越低
the observed trajectory kept getting lower and lower to the point
以至于他们看到它一直下降到只有150公里
where they saw it go all the way down to just 150 kilometers,
但那还是安全地超过了80公里的最低海拔高度
but that was still safely above the minimum altitude of 80 kilometers.
现在如果你到80公里以下的高度
Now if you go below 80 kilometers
火星的大气层仍然会咬住你那脆弱的小飞船 把它撕成碎片
Mars's atmosphere will still bite up your fragile little spacecraft and rip it to shreds.
[你现在无能为力]
剧透警告
想象一下那块脆弱的小太阳能电池板被火星风吹得七零八落
Just imagine that tiny little fragile solar panel getting knocked about by the Martian winds.
哦 太可怜了
Oh, humanity.
就在轨道进入机动点火前24小时
Just 24 hours before the orbital insertion burn
火星的引力效应越来越强
as the gravitational effects of Mars grew stronger
新观测到的轨道将把航天器置于仅110公里的高度
the newly observed trajectory was putting the spacecraft at only 110 kilometers.
但同样 这仍然高于80公里 这是能让探测器存活下来
But again, that's still above the 80 kilometers that's survivable.
因此 他们继续进行 尽管一些操作人员直言反对
So they proceeded despite some vocal opposition of some of the operators.
1999年9月23日 UTC 09:46
At 9 o'clock and 46 seconds UTC on September 23 1999,
进入机动点火开始
the insertion burn began.
最初一切都按计划进行
Everything was performing as planned at first.
任务管理中心预期在飞船去往火星背面时信号会丢失
Miss control expected a loss of signal when the spacecraft went behind Mars,
他们希望这些事会按时发生
and they had an exact time they expected that to happen.
大麻烦的第一个苗头出现了
The first signs of serious trouble cropped up
信号的丢失较预期早49秒发生
when the loss of signal occurred 49 seconds earlier than expected,
并且问题愈演愈糟
and it was even further drilled in by the fact
因为信号在晚于预计的21分钟后仍未出现
that signal was not required 21 minutes later as they expected,
尽管(在此之后)尝试了整整两天
despite trying for two full days.
我很遗憾地报告 关于火星气候探测器 我们有一个严重问题
- I'm sorry to report that we have a serious problem with the Mars Climate Orbiter.
事实上我们可能正面临任务的失败
We may in fact be facing a loss of mission.
那么到底发生了什么
- So what actually happened?
是进入机动点火有什么问题吗
Was there something wrong with the insertion burn?
是不是NASA读取的单位是公里而探测器传回的是英里
Was it that NASA was reading the oxygen kilometers when the probe was saying miles.
听完本周赞助商香蕉度量的一席话 我们就知道了
Find out after we hear a word from this week's sponsor, banana for scale.
油管民间火箭博主
你是否厌倦了基于几个老家伙的脚测量东西
- Are you tired of measuring stuff based on some old guy's feet?
[尖叫]
[screaming]
油管航天考古学博主
给虫有翻译过她的视频av97474191
你是否经常问Siri的多少盎司是一品脱 只得到错误的答案
Are you constantly asking Siri how many ounces are in a pint, only to get the wrong answer?
嘿Siri 多少盎司是一品脱
- Hey Siri, how many ounces are in a pint?
奥斯汀是美国马萨诸塞州的首府
- [Siri] Austin is the capital of Massachusetts?
爱荷华州(每日宇航员老家)的一家红茶菌饮料店
知道一升有一千毫升是不是太容易了
- Is it just too easy knowing there's a 1000 milliliters in a litre?
或者 也许你正在用手测量马 而你实在没法儿@#$%^
Or perhaps you're measuring horses in hands and you just can't even...
油管Starship直播博主，
在南牧师岛上
（South Padre Island），
距离Starship测试场大概9km
Introducing banana for scale the one true unit of measure.
3件仅需42.69刀
再加上仅需19.99刀的运费和手续费
电视
推荐
30天无条件退款！
来了解下香蕉度量 这可是唯一真正的度量单位
Introducing banana for scale the one true unit of measure.
好了 所以这是答案 每次飞船执行那些去饱和机动
- Okay, so the answer each and every time the spacecraft perform those desaturation maneuvers,
它会汇报它做了什么来校正角动量
it would report back what it did to correct for the angular momentum.
由于卫星内部的导航和控制系统的表现完美
Now the internal guidance and control was performing perfectly fine.
保持控制及飞船的正确方向是没问题的
Maintaining control and keeping proper orientation of the spacecraft no problem.
问题在于飞船发回地球的单位是牛顿秒
The problem is what the space craft was sending back down to earth was Newton seconds.
而在地面站的软件用磅秒读那些结果
And the software in the ground station was reading those results as pound seconds.
并将偏离了4.45倍的结果报告给制导和导航团队
And reporting those results to the guidance and navigation teams off by a factor of 4.45 times.
因此换句话说 每当飞船做一个去饱和机动
So in other words, each time the spacecraft did a desaturation maneuver,
它都会给地面精确地报告它做了什么
it reported back to the ground what exactly it did.
[来自阿波罗时代的影像，显然不是90年代末的状况]
它都会给地面精确地报告它做了什么
it reported back to the ground what exactly it did.
使用错误单位的数据
The data with the wrong unit,
由导航团队输入到用于(计算)探测器轨道的模型
then was put into the model for the spacecraft's trajectory by the guidance team.
现在 既然单位是错误的
Now since the units were wrong,
计算出的轨道也是错误的
the calculated trajectory was also wrong.
现在 有意思的是 因为这些角动量去饱和度点火的能量如此之低
Now the funny thing is because these angular momentum desaturation burns were so low energy
偏离4.45倍是难以察觉的
being off by 4.45 times was hardly noticeable.
所以整个旅程
So throughout the journey,
那些微小的事件 每一个都只做了一点点
every one of those little tiny events was doing a tiny little bit,
但预计的轨迹认为他们多做了约4.45倍的工作量
but the estimated trajectory thought they were doing about 4.45 times more work.
由于火星气候轨道器只有一块太阳能电池板 这就更复杂了
This was compounded by the fact that because the Mars Climate Orbiter had just a single solar panel,
它得比它的姊妹探测器超过10倍地执行去饱和机动
it had to perform over 10 times more desaturation events than its sister spacecraft,
火星全球勘测者有两块太阳能板
the Mars Global Surveyor, which had two solar panels.
那么如何才能避免这种情况的发生呢
So how could this have been prevented?
好了 像很多东西一样 很容易把责任推到一个人或一群人
Well, like most things, it'd be easy to put blame on one person or group
但在现实中 它是一系列小的问题
but in reality, it's kind of a whole swath of small problems
而诿过于人并没有真正解决问题
and putting the blame on anyone doesn't really solve the problem.
第一个也是最明显的问题和解决方案是确保所有单位都是一样的
The first and most obvious problem and solution is to make sure all units are the same.
洛克希德·马丁公司因为使用磅秒单位受到了很多指责
Lockheed Martin took a lot of flack for delivering units in pounds seconds,
因为它本来就应该以牛秒交付的
as it was intended to be delivered in Newton's seconds.
但奇怪的是 指责的游戏仍在继续
But oddly, the blame game continues.
当人们发现给洛克希德·马丁公司的代码一开始就是以磅秒为单位的
When it was discovered the code given to Lockheed Martin was in pound seconds in the first place,
他们没有发现
and they didn't catch it.
具体来说是一个叫微小力的代码集
Specifically a set of code called Small forces,
这是从一开始就有的错误
which was wrong from day one.
好了 然后再次 没有人抓到 NASA质量控制也没有
Well, and then again, that no one caught the air and quality control at NASA either.
然后你就可以继续下去 说这是一个管理问题
And then you can keep going and saying it was a management problem,
考虑到从航天器的最初设计开始就忽略了几个因素
considering several things factors were overlooked starting with the initial design of the spacecraft.
最值得注意的是 设计团队中没人负责过导航和控制
Most notably that no one from guidance and navigation was on the design team,
这首先就导致了探测器的导航不够理想
which led to a less than desirable and hard to navigate spacecraft in the first place.
但这之后又忽略了导航团队的要求
But then ignoring the requests of the guidance navigation team
进行相隔180度的饱和机动
to perform the desaturation maneuvers 180 degrees apart from each other
就会在问题出现之前就将其抵消
would have negated the problem before it arose.
(与导航团队的要求不同) 不对称点火的去饱和机动也会增加多余的速度
By doing asymmetrical burns for the desaturation also led to imparting additional unwanted velocity.
最后
And lastly,
各小组看到的错误数据与我们计算的轨迹不一致
the teams were seeing erroneous data that didn't line up with our calculated trajectories,
但它被忽略了
but it was ignored.
这一点被放大了 而且很明显的是
This was amplified and actually quite obvious
在任务的最后一周 随着航天器离火星越来越近 出现了一些问题
that something was wrong in the last week of the mission as the spacecraft got closer to Mars.
团队的一些成员口头表达过
A few members of the team spoke up verbally
并希望做一个提前24小时的纠正点火以提高接近轨道
and wanted to do a t-minus 24 hour correction burn to raise the approach.
但他们被拒绝了 因为他们的担心没有正确提出
But they were denied because the concerns weren't filed correctly.
而且由于一些权威的错误组织
And due to some misorganization of authority.
求弹幕憋住，我已经改翻译了！求生欲.jpg
那些人被看作是犯规的
Those that spoke up were seen as out of line.
黑白震怒
所以 和其他事一样 这不是黑与白的话题
So really like all things, this wasn't a black and white topic.
它相当微妙 有很多细小的事情 加起来就是一件大事
It's fairly nuanced and has a lot of tiny little things that added up to one big thing.
并且在最后
And at the end of the day,
事情发生了 我们能做的最好的事是从中吸取教训
the thing happened and the best thing we can do is learn from it
并阻止其再次发生
and prevent it from ever happening again.
事实上 在火星气候探测器发现的这些问题
In fact, the problems discovered with the Mars Climate Orbiter
在火星极地着陆者上交叉检查了
was cross checked with the Mars Polar Lander,
它同时也在前往火星的路上
which was also on its way to Mars at the exact same time.
虽然它没有同样的问题
And although it didn't have the same problem,
它最终没有软着陆 失败原因完全不同
it ended up not touching down softly for completely different reason.
Volcom 火星操作员
- Volcom Mars op.
CFOM 继续
- CFOM, go ahead.
是啊 Sam 我很遗憾地通知我们现在只有HKTM
- Yeah, Sam, I'm sorry to report that all we have is HKTM at this point.
这似乎是没有正常地联系到MR Pass
It seemed to have been a nominal no contact MR Pass
收到 Mark 感谢坚持与我们联系
- Copy that Mark thanks for, thank for hanging in there with us.
但这一教训却被传给了每一个新一代的导航员和工程师
- But the lesson learned has been passed down to every new generation of navigators and engineers.
这是一个宝贵的经验
It's a valuable lesson and hopefully a lesson everyone
希望那些研制第一批载人登火航天器的每个人都能认真吸取教训
who designed spacecraft for the first humans going to Mars has listened to closely.
那么总结下
So to summarize,
奔赴火星的航天器
a spacecraft on its way to Mars
需要对抗施加在单面太阳能电池板上的太阳光压
needed to fight off the solar pressure exerted onto the single sided solar panel
通过用小型姿态推进器做一些角动量去饱和机动
by doing some angular momentum desaturations with its small attitude thrusters.
每次航天器做了一个去饱和机动
Each time the vehicle did a desaturation maneuver,
它记录它的做了什么 并报告回地球
it recorded what it did and reported it back down to earth
这里软件对推进器点火的记录
where the recorded thruster firings were misinterpreted by software
误读为磅秒的力而不是牛秒的力
as pounds seconds of force instead of Newton seconds,
导致计算出的轨道出现非常微小的偏差
leading to very tiny deviations in the calculated trajectory.
这些微小的偏差如此之小
These tiny deviations were so small,
它们大多没有被注意到 直到航天器在57公里的高空掠过火星
they went mostly unnoticed until the spacecraft encountered Mars at 57 kilometers in altitude,
而不是计算的226公里
instead of the calculated 226 kilometers,
这很可能使航天器在火星大气层中被烧掉
which likely made the spacecraft burn up in the Martian atmosphere,
导致任务的失败
leading to the loss of the mission.
因此 当我们犯一些小错误时 不要对自己如此刻薄
So let's not be so hard on ourselves when we make little errors.
或者 对彼此更好一点
Or maybe be nicer to each other
理解我们每个人都会犯错
understanding each and every single one of us is capable of mistakes.
它只是作为人类的一部分
It's simply part of being human.
所以你怎么想
So what do you think?
你学到了什么
Did you learn something?
你认为这只是一个简单的单位错误吗
Do you think it's just a simple unit error?
还是说你认为还有更多的原因
Or do you think there's a lot more to it than that?
让我知道你的想法 以及为什么公制是更好的测量单位 在下面评论
Let me know your thoughts and why metric is the better unit of measurement in the comments below.
现在我保证我会多做几个这样的太空相关视频来试试
Now I promise I'll do a few more of these space POM videos to try
以尝试并填补我的一些长视频之间的间隔
and fill the gap between some of my long form videos.
因为相信我 那些对我来说也变得有点夸张了
Because trust me, those are getting a bit ridiculous even for me.
I owe a huge thank you to my Patreon supporters for helping make content like this possible.
I have the best community of people that help me research and script these videos.
And fact check before this all comes public.
So they let me know if I've done anything wrong.
And it's actually a really fun place to hang out.
So if you wanna gain access to our exclusive subreddit,
our exclusive discord channel and exclusive live streams
and just hang out with really awesome space enthusiasts go to patreon.com/everydayastronaut.
And while you're online,
be sure to check out my awesome webstore for shirts like this pointy end up flaming down,
or the lunar mission shirt or the brand new future Martian society shirt.
There's just lots of cool stuff.
So check back often these are all limited run
and they might not be there the next time you check back.
That's everydayastronaut.com/shop.
Thanks everybody.
That's gonna do it for me.
我是Tim Dodd 每日宇航员
I'm Tim Dodd, the everyday astronaut.
将太空的知识带给地球上的普通人
Bringing space down to earth for everyday people.
[令人振奋的音乐]
[upbeat music]